1. In your own words, explain what clean code is and why it is important.
A: Clean code is code that is easy for humans to read, understand, and maintain. Ideally it is as simple as possible, with no repetition, extensive nesting, 
over-engineering or other complications. It is important because code will be maintained by more than one person, and it would be a waste of time
to spend more time figuring out what code does/how it is structured. Also, repetition can lead to bugs if the person doesn't realize that things are repeated 
and only alter them in one instance.

2. Read this article about Toyota and their use of bad code. Although you may not yet understand all of the topics discussed, think about another commonly used object that relies on computers and explain what would happen if the code was not created to an acceptable standard.
A: Credit card/RFID scanners in stores could cause huge problems if code is not to standard. In an increasingly cashless society, software bugs that limit
our access to money or compromise card security would be inconvenient at best and potentially cause a panic.

3.Would you consider the following to be clean code? Explain why or why not. If not, refactor the code.


FUNCTION do(x, y)               // Creating a new function
 IF y = "F" THEN               // Check if y is equal "F"
 SET z to (x−32) * (5/9)       // Formula to convert degrees fahrenheit to celsius
 PRINT z                       // Print result
 ELSE IF y = "C" THEN          // If y not equal to "F", check if equal to "C"
 SET z to x * 1.8000 + 32.00   // Formula to convert degrees celsius to fahrenheit
 PRINT z                       // Print result
 END IF
END FUNCTION

No, because it does two different things based on the input, I would rather have it as 2 functions:

FUNCTION toCelsius(x, y)       // Creating a new function
 IF y = "F" THEN               // Check if y is equal "F"
 SET z to (x−32) * (5/9)       // Formula to convert degrees fahrenheit to celsius
 PRINT z                       // Print result
END FUNCTION

FUNCTION toFahrenheit(x,y)    
 IF y = "C" THEN	       // If y not equal to "F", check if equal to "C"
 SET z to x * 1.8000 + 32.00   // Formula to convert degrees celsius to fahrenheit
 PRINT z                       // Print result
 END IF
END FUNCTION


4. Would you consider the following to be clean code? Explain why or why not. If not, refactor the code.
A: This looks fine, it only has the one operation and an error message if the operation can't be done

FUNCTION calcPercent(sum, total)
 IF NOT(total = 0) THEN
     SET percentage to sum / total * 100
 ELSE
   PRINT "Sorry, cannot divide by 0"
 END IF

 PRINT percentage
END FUNCTION

5.Using pseudocode, refactor the code for the following examples using the principles you have learned in this checkpoint.

a. The following function prints the subtotal of a customer's transaction and receives payment accordingly.

FUNCTION checkOutCustomer(subTotal, discountRate, paymentType)
   VARIABLE totalDue = subTotal * discountRate + (subTotal * tax)
   PRINT "Your total due is: " + totalDue

   IF paymentType = 'CASH' THEN
       CALL getPayment RETURNING amount
       PRINT "Change due: " + amount - totalDue
   ELSE IF paymentType = 'CREDIT CARD' THEN
       CALL getPayment RETURNING amount
       PRINT "Your credit card has been charged: " + totalDue
   END IF
END FUNCTION

b. The following function checks out a book if there are no issues with the guest's account.

IF isEligible(guest) THEN
  CALL checkoutBook WITH book and guest
  ELSE 
     PRINT "Unable to check out book."

FUNCTION checkoutBook(book, guest)
   APPEND book to guest.books
   SET book.status to "Checked Out"
   PRINT "Your books have been issued."
END FUNCTION

FUNCTION isEligible(guest) 
  RETURN guest.accountActive AND NOT(guest.hasOverdueBooks) AND guest.outstandingFees = 0
END FUNCTION

c. The following class is a code snippet that should support the transactions a customer can perform at an ATM.

CLASS BankAccount

 FUNCTION displayBalance
    PRINT balance
 END FUNCTION

 FUNCTION deposit(amount)
    SET balance to balance + amount
 END FUNCTION

 FUNCTION withdraw(amount)
     IF balance > amount THEN
       SET balance to balance - amount
     END
 END FUNCTION

END CLASS

CLASS OptionalOffers 

 FUNCTION creditCardOffer
     IF NOT(customer.hasCreditCard) THEN
         CALL offerCreditCard
     END
 END FUNCTION

 FUNCTION checkStatus
     IF NOT(customer.hasCheckingAccount) THEN
         CALL offerCheckingAccount
     END
 END FUNCTION
END CLASS
 ....
 ....
 ....



Programming Questions
You may do the following problems in any language of your choice. Use the clean code principles taught in this section while writing the code.

6. Square Given an array of integers, find out whether the sum of the integers is a perfect square. If it is a perfect square, return the square root, otherwise return the sum.

Example:
[10,1,4,6,1,1,2] returns 5 because the square root of 25 is 5.
[1,1] returns 2 because 2 is not a perfect square.
The square root of 2 is approximately 1.414213562373095.

function sumArray(arr) {
  const reducer = (accumulator, currentValue) => accumulator + currentValue;
  let sumTotal = arr.reduce(reducer)
  return sumTotal;
}

function findSquare(sumTotal) {
  squareRoot = Math.sqrt(sumTotal)
    if (Number.isInteger(squareRoot)) {
      console.log(squareRoot)
    } else {
      console.log(sumTotal)
    }
}

7. Duplicate Given an array of integers, find out whether the array contains any duplicate elements. The function should return true if any value appears at least twice in the array, and false if every element is distinct.

var findDuplicate = function(a) {
  var counts = [];
  for(var i = 0; i < a.length; i++) {
    if(counts[a[i]] === undefined) {
      counts[a[i]] = 1;
    } else {
      return true;
    }
  }
  return false
}

Extra Credit
8. Anagram An anagram is a word, phrase, or name formed by rearranging the letters of another word. For example, spar can be formed from rasp. Given two strings, stringOne and stringTwo, determine if stringOne is an anagram of stringTwo. Assume that the strings contain only lowercase letters and do not worry about case-sensitivity. Hint: Your first task will be to convert the strings to arrays.